JUJUTSU KAISEN
The Culling Game Part 1
Nice to meet you.
Child of Zen'in, Descendant of Michizane,
Cursed Womb Death Painting,
and Vessel of Sukuna.
No greeting for me, Tengen?
So this...
So this thing...
So this person...
Person?
...is Tengen?!
It's not our first time meeting,
Yuki Tsukumo.
Why did you close the Tombs of the Star?
I was wary of you being
aligned with Kenjaku.
I can't tell what's going on
in people's hearts, after all.
Kenjaku?
What was once Noritoshi Kamo.
The sorcerer currently inhabiting
Suguru Geto's body.
A net of compassion and
a rope of salvation, huh?
He didn't even try for
sarcasm with that name.
Why are you like that, Tengen-sama?
Ballsy of him to insert himself
into the conversation there...
I'm immortal, but not ageless.
You'd look like this, too,
if you were 500 years old.
Seriously?
Since I failed to assimilate
with the Star Plasma Vessel twelve
years ago, my aging has accelerated,
and my identity as an
individual has vanished,
so the world itself is who I am now.
So there wasn't actually another
Star Plasma Vessel back then?
That explains why there isn't a new voice.
Excuse me.
We came here to learn Kenjaku's goal
and how to open the Prison Realm.
Could you tell us what you know?
Of course.
Or so I'd like to say, but I
must impose one condition.
Yuta Okkotsu.
Yuki Tsukumo.
Cursed Womb Death Painting.
I'll need two of you three to remain here
and guard me.
Guard you? But you're immortal, right?
Are you afraid of being sealed or something?
That isn't fair.
You won't tell us why or
how long we're guarding you?
In that case,
let me speak of Kenjaku.
Kenjaku's Objective
That man's objective
is to force the evolution of
mankind throughout all of Japan.
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
I heard about that.
But how does he actually intend to do it?
Why didn't Kenjaku use your barriers
to turn everyone in Japan
into jujutsu sorcerers
Idle Transfiguration
with Idle Transfiguration back then?
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
Because he simply lacked the
cursed energy to do that.
The cursed energy refined through
Maelstrom can't return to the sorcerer.
Insufficient Cursed Energy
Also, evolving people one person at a time
with a cursed technique is far too inefficient.
Kenjaku's Objective
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
How?
Assimilate Mankind With Tengen
Why?
Unknown
So the method of evolution
that Kenjaku has chosen
is to assimilate mankind with me.
How?
Assimilate Mankind With {}Tengen
Huh? But your assimilation...
...should only be possible with
the Star Plasma Vessel.
Tengen
Star Plasma Vessel
Ordinary Person
Assimilation Possible
Assimilation Impossible
Previously, that was true.
Star Plasma Vessel's Death
Assimilation With the Star Plasma Vessel Prevented
But since I started evolving
twelve years ago,
Tengen
Tengen's Evolution
assimilation with someone other than
the Star Plasma Vessel is possible.
Assimilate Mankind With Tengen
But you're just one person, right?
How would you assimilate
with multiple people?
What you see before you right
now isn't my real self.
Now that I've evolved,
my soul is everywhere.
I told you, didn't I?
The world itself is who I am now.
People who assimilated with me now would
become something more than a sorcerer.
They would become a new being
that's both there and not there.
I'm able to retain my shape and reason
after evolving because of
my barrier techniques.
However, if mankind were to evolve,
then if even one of them
went out of control,
Out of Control
the world would end.
Why?
There would be no boundaries
between individuals,
so evil would spread to all instantly.
Out of Control
The impurities of a hundred million
people would flood the world.
What happened in Tokyo would be
recreated on a worldwide scale.
Why would he do such a thing?
Kenjaku's Objective
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
How?
Why?
Assimilate Mankind With Tengen
Unknown
I don't know.
I told you that, too.
I can't tell what's going
on in people's hearts.
Kenjaku's Objective
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
How?
Why?
Assimilate Mankind With Tengen
Unknown
Why?
But wouldn't everything be fine as long
as you rejected the assimilation?
That's the issue.
Now that I've evolved, my nature is closer to
that of a Cursed Spirit than a human.
Suguru Geto's Death
Obtained Cursed Spirit Manipulation
Obtained Idle Transfiguration
Star Plasma Vessel's Death
Tengen's Evolution
Obtain Tengen
So I can be
targeted by Cursed Spirit Manipulation.
Considering Kenjaku's
strength as a sorcerer,
I would likely be absorbed
the moment he made contact.
That's why my main body is rejecting
everything in the
Tombs of the Star right now.
That's why you want us to guard you?
Yes.
Kenjaku is second only to me in
his skill with barrier techniques.
I don't know when he'll manage to break
the seal on the Tombs of the Star.
Why now?
You were stopped from assimilating
with the Star Plasma Vessel.
Assimilation With Star Plasma Vessel Prevented
Now you've been forced to evolve,
Tengen's Evolution
and he seeks to absorb you with
Cursed Energy Manipulation.
Obtain Tengen
Assimilation With Star Plasma Vessel Prevented
Tengen's Evolution
Obtain Tengen
Kenjaku also seems to have
connections to Sukuna.
So he's been a sorcerer
for at least 1,000 years.
So why now?!
Tengen
Because I, the Star Plasma
Vessel, and the Six Eyes
Star Plasma Vessel
Six Eyes
are all connected by fate.
Kenjaku's Objective
Stop Tengen's Assimilation
Twice in the past, Kenjaku was stopped
by the sorcerer with the Six Eyes.
The second time, Kenjaku was thorough.
Kenjaku's Objective
Stop Tengen's Assimilation
He killed both the Star
Plasma Vessel and the bearer
of the Six Eyes within
a month of their birth.
Despite that, the Six Eyes
and the Star Plasma Vessel
still appeared by the
day of my assimilation.
After that, Kenjaku altered his
strategy to focus on sealing
the Six Eyes instead of killing him,
and he began searching
for the Prison Realm,
because there can't be two people
with the Six Eyes at the same time.
Kenjaku's Objective
However, twelve years ago,
something unpredictable happened.
Toji Zen'in intervened.
Unpredicted Event
Toji Zen'in Intervenes
He was physically gifted
through a Heavenly Pact.
And he was unique among them
for being completely
free from cursed energy.
Kenjaku's Objective
Since his Heavenly Pact
placed him outside of fate,
Zen'in Toji Intervenes
he destroyed the fate connecting us.
Star Plasma Vessel's Death
Then a young man with power of
Cursed Spirit Manipulation appeared.
Star Plasma Vessel's Death
Cursed Spirit Manipulation
Without even trying,
he now had all the necessary pieces
other than the Prison Realm.
Then, six years ago,
the Prison Realm made its way
into Kenjaku's hands, as well.
Prison Realm
The Culling Game
Then why is this
Culling Game being hosted?
It's a warm-up before assimilation.
Mankind
Tengen
My assimilation with people other
than the Star Plasma Vessel is possible,
Assimilation
but at the moment,
there's a high probability
Incomplete
it will result in something incomplete.
The Culling Game
The Culling Game uses the
cursed energy of the Players
and the boundaries formed
between the Colonies
Mankind
Tengen
The Culling Game
in a ritual to send this nation's
people to the other side.
Warm-Up
He probably plans to use that as a warm-up
Assimilation
Success
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
to start their assimilation with me.
The Culling Game
Mankind
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
Tengen
However, in order to establish that ritual,
The Culling Game
Kenjaku should have been forced
to accept several pacts.
The Culling Game
Details
7: The Game Master must approve any additional rules
requested under Rule 6 above, except when
the Rule would significantly hinder
the continuation of the Culling Game.
One of them is that Kenjaku cannot be the
Game Master of the Culling Game himself.
7: The Game Master must approve any additional rules
requested under Rule 6 above, except when
the Rule would significantly hinder
the continuation of the Culling Game.
However, that still serves as
a disadvantage to you all,
because it means that killing Kenjaku
won't end the Culling Game.
Player
Either all of the Players must die,
Dead
Player
or the Players must all refuse
to participate and die.
Refuse to Participate
Dead
7: The Game Master must
The Culling Game won't end until then.
The "continuation" mentioned
in the Culling Game's rules
hinder the continuation
is insurance to prevent the
ritual from being stopped.
In that case...
Yeah.
6: By spending 100 points, not counting
the initial point value assigned to them,
Players may negotiate with the Game Master
to add an additional Rule to the Culling Game.
6: By spending 100 points, not counting the initial point value assigned to them,
Players may negotiate with the Game Master to add an additional Rule to the Culling Game.
We'll need to participate
in the Culling Game,
and add a rule that creates
a way out of the game
By spending 100 points
add an additional Rule
for Tsumiki-san and those
reluctant to participate.
We also need to free Gojo-sensei
at the same time.
That man could resolve
everything on his own.
Itadori's Friends' Objective
Create a Rule to Escape the Culling Game
Free Satoru Gojo
Tengen-sama.
Tell us.
First, please decide who will stay.
I will stay.
Yuji, you will absolutely need the
help of Okkotsu or that woman.
Kamo Noritoshi...
If Kenjaku is coming after Tengen,
that's all the more reason for me to stay.
Because slaying him will
save my younger brothers.
I'm still not finished
talking with Tengen.
Is that okay, Okkotsu-kun?
Yes!
I don't want to be separated
from everyone anymore, either!
Thank you.
This...
is the "Back" of the Prison Realm
that you'll need in order
to free Satoru Gojo.
Prison Realm Back
Back?!
First I've heard of it.
You mean like a back door?
That's right.
Before Kenjaku found it,
the Prison Realm was
outside of my barriers.
Probably somewhere abroad.
Prison Realm
By keeping this Back sealed,
I concealed the presence of the Front,
Satoru Gojo
but it didn't work.
Prison Realm Back
Satoru Gojo is also sealed
away within this back gate.
Huh?! Then if we open it...
No, the authority to open the gates rests
with the owner of the Front—Kenjaku.
In order to break this one open,
Prison Realm Back
you need either the Inverted
Spear of Heaven that can force
the cancellation of cursed techniques,
Inverted Spear of Heaven
or the Black Rope that can
disrupt and cancel out the effects
Black Rope
of a cursed technique.
Inverted Spear of Heaven
However, twelve years ago,
Satoru Gojo either sealed the Inverted
Spear of Heaven abroad or destroyed it.
Why'd you do that, Sensei?!
Black Rope
The Black Rope was also completely
expended against Satoru Gojo last year.
What was that man thinking?!
Oh.
Miguel-san and I were searching
Africa for more of that Black Rope.
So that's why you were abroad.
It was a complete waste of effort, though.
They said it's all gone.
Huh?!
There's still some way, right?
Yes.
Among the Players participating
in the Culling Game,
Prison Realm Back
Inverted Spear of Heaven
Black Rope
there's a sorcerer from 1,000 years
ago who calls herself "Angel."
Angel
Her cursed technique can extinguish
any other cursed technique.
Hana Kurusu
Episode 50
About the Culling Game
Satoru Gojo
Prison Realm
Prison Realm Back
Angel
Extinguish any cursed technique?
Yes.
The Angel's cursed technique can
open the Back of the Prison Realm.
Do you know where she is right now?
She's in the Colony on
the east side of Tokyo.
The Culling Game's barriers reject me,
so I don't have more
information than that.
Let's start going over things from there.
There are ten Colonies across Japan.
They are linked by barriers designed to
ferry the people of
Japan to the other side.
Crossing a river or other border—
Yasohachi Bridge's River
Other Side
Colonies' Barriers
acts that symbolize crossing
to the afterlife—
carry important meaning in sorcery.
Oh, it's like with Yasohachi Bridge!
Is Hokkaido excluded because of
the Jujutsu Society's barrier?
That's right.
That land is already established
as a vast sacred ground.
That's "the challenging land" for you.
*"The Challenging Land"
The catchphrase issued in '99 by
the Hokkaido Government Office.
The Culling Game
Warm-Up
Assimilate Mankind With Tengen
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
"Ferry them to the other side"
may sound dramatic,
but everyone in Japan was cursed in
preparation for the assimilation.
Warm-Up Complete
The Culling Game
How long will this ritual take to complete?
That depends on the Culling Game,
but it'll probably be
over within two months.
1: After awakening their Cursed Technique,
players must go to a Colony of their choice within 19 days
and pledge their participation in the Culling Game.
1: After awakening their Cursed Technique,
players must go to a Colony of their choice within 19 days
and pledge their participation in the Culling Game.
It's currently 9 AM on November 9th.
The Players awakened as sorcerers
around midnight on October 31st.
We have about ten days and fifteen hours
before Tsumiki's forced to participate.
Remaining Time Until Tsumiki
Must Enter the Culling Game
Obtain 100 points and add a rule
allowing people to escape.
2: Players breaching the first rule shall be
stripped of their technique.
Tengen-sama, you said earlier
2: Players breaching the first rule shall be
stripped of their technique.
that people would die if
they refused to participate.
stripped of their technique.
Yes.
Stripped of their technique?
That rule also applies to sorcerers
joining in later, right?
Then the stripping isn't being
done by Idle Transfiguration.
It says "stripped," not "prohibited
from using," so it's not a pact, either.
That means it'll be doing something
to the brain by force,
and it's better for the rules if
being stripped means death, too.
Otherwise, everyone would
refuse to participate.
It's just as Shoko-san anticipated,
but that also means there's no risk
to sorcerers without any
cursed technique, like me.
And what'll happen to Panda?
Does he even have a brain?
3: Non-Players shall become Players upon
entering a Colony, and their entry shall be taken
as pledging to participate in the Culling Game.
What does this rule mean for the ordinary
people who were in the Colony from the start?
3: Non-Players shall become Players upon
entering a Colony, and their entry shall be taken
as pledging to participate in the Culling Game.
It means they're granted at
least one chance to leave.
For real?
That's awfully generous.
There are no stipulations in the rules
about leaving or entering Colonies.
They were probably aiming to stimulate the
Culling Game by giving Players a clear,
upon entering
initial goal of leaving the Colony.
In order to keep the Players inside,
the premise that Players "entered of
their own free will" is important.
The thing about adjusting the barrier
strength that Ino-san mentioned?
4: Players will receive points upon
ending the life of another Player.
ending the life
5: Points shall be designated based on the value
that the Game Master gives their life,
and fundamentally, a sorcerer will be worth
5 points while non-sorcerers will be worth 1 point.
5: Points shall be designated based on the value
that the Game Master gives their life,
and fundamentally, a sorcerer will be worth
5 points while non-sorcerers will be worth 1 point.
Using "fundamentally" within a rule?
Way to make things confusing.
fundamentally
a sorcerer will be worth 5 points
non-sorcerers will be worth 1 point.
Fushiguro?
Game Master
It's nothing.
Tengen-sama, who is this Game Master?
Game Master
Every individual Player is given
a shikigami called "Kogane."
Kogane
Not the Game Master
To be precise, Kogane isn't the
Game Master—it's an interface.
It's best to think of the Culling Game
system itself as the Game Master.
I see...
5: Points shall be designated based on the value
that the Game Master gives their life,
and fundamentally, a sorcerer will be worth
5 points while non-sorcerers will be worth 1 point.
6: By spending 100 points, not counting
the initial point value assigned to them,
Players may negotiate with the Game Master
to add an additional Rule to the Culling Game.
6: By spending 100 points, not counting
the initial point value assigned to them,
Players may negotiate with the Game Master
to add an additional Rule to the Culling Game.
"Add," huh?
100 points
So no eliminating any existing rules.
add an additional Rule
6: By spending 100 points, not counting
the initial point value assigned to them,
Players may negotiate with the Game Master
to add an additional Rule to the culling game.
We might be able to refute
them in a roundabout way.
7: The Game Master must approve any additional rules
requested under Rule 6 above, except when
the Rule would significantly hinder
the continuation of the Culling Game.
7: The Game Master must approve any additional rules
requested under Rule 6 above, except when
the Rule would significantly hinder
the continuation of the Culling Game.
Is this allowed?
Right?
It leans too heavily on their judgment.
7: The Game Master must approve any additional rules
requested under Rule 6 above, except when
the Rule would significantly hinder
the continuation of the culling game.
No, you should be able to
expect a fair decision here.
They're already imposing such
strong rules on the Players.
Jujutsu sorcery wouldn't allow them
to favor Kenjaku any further.
8: Players who do not show a
change in points within 19 days of
joining or acquiring points
shall be stripped of their technique.
8: Players who do not show a
change in points within 19 days of
joining or acquiring points
shall be stripped of their technique.
So I'll kill people again?
do not show
No, I have a few ideas.
a change
8: Players who do not show a
change in points within 19 days of
joining or acquiring points
shall be stripped of their technique.
The Culling Game
We've managed to organize
our information for now.
That just leaves the roles for each of us.
Future Actions
Choso
Yuki Tsukumo
Yuki-san and Choso will remain
here to guard Tengen-sama.
Guard Tengen
Maki Zen'in
I need to return to the Zen'in house
and retrieve their cursed tools.
Retrieve Cursed Tools from the Zen'in Clan
Shortly after Satoru was sealed,
the Kamo and Zen'in Clans
both took their cursed tools
out of Jujutsu High's
forbidden vault, so it's empty.
However, Megumi's now the
head of the Zen'in Clan.
Oh?!
I'll explain later.
Thanks to that, we're free to rummage
through the Zen'in Clan's forbidden vault.
But before that, Tengen-sama...
Maki Zen'in
Retrieve Cursed Tools from the Zen'in Clan
I know.
Juzo Kumiya's atelier, right?
Juzo Kumiya's Atelier
Thank you.
Once I'm finished, I'll look for Panda
and help deal with the Culling Game.
And you, Yuta?
Maki Zen'in
Juzo Kumiya's Atelier
Retrieve Cursed Tools From the Zen'in Clan
Okkotsu
I'll enter a Colony and participate
in the Culling Game right away.
Participate in the Culling Game
Meet Up With Panda
I'd like to gather as much
information as possible
before Tsumiki-san and Fushiguro-kun
Participate in the Culling Game
participate in the Culling Game.
Thank you.
It'll mean acting on my own again,
but to prevent us from
clashing with each other,
and to avoid running into her if
something does happen to Tsumiki-san,
I'll stay away from the nearby Colonies.
The Colonies might cut off reception,
so I might be out of
contact for a while...
If Sukuna does manage
to take control again,
don't hesitate to kill me.
They're thinking that having Okkotsu near
Itadori would keep Fushiguro safe, but it
would be a more efficient use of their
forces for Okkotsu to act alone.
Is this the time to worry about that?
It'll be fine.
If that happens, you can
have him kill you after I die.
No, I'm trying to prevent that.
Senpai.
Megumi Fushiguro
Yuji Itadori
Yeah.
You two go to see Kinji like we planned.
Meet Up With Kinji Hakari
Kinji?
Kinji Hakari.
Kinji Hakari
The suspended third-year.
We're shorthanded right now.
Do whatever it takes to recruit him.
Is he strong?
He's a bit capricious,
but when he gets into it,
he's stronger than me.
That's impossible.
Kenjaku's Objective (Road Map)
1 Year Ago
Suguru Geto's Death
Obtained Cursed Spirit Manipulation
Absorbed Mahito
Obtained Idle Transfiguration
Turn Mankind Throughout All Japan
Into Sorcerers With Idle Transfiguration
Insufficient Cursed Energy
12 Years Ago
Toji Zen'in Intervenes
Amanai Riko Murdered
6 Years Ago
Obtained Prison Realm
Assimilate
Star Plasma
Vessel
Tengen
October 31st
Satoru Gojo Sealed
Guard   Fate
Six Eyes
Assimilation Failed
Tengen's Evolution
Becomes a Target for
Cursed Spirit Manipulation
Assimilation With People Aside from
the Star Plasma Vessel Becomes Possible
Goal: Warm-Up for Assimilation
Absorb Tengen With Cursed Spirit Manipulation
The Culling Game
Make Modern Sorcerers and Sorcerers Awakened
or Incarnated Through Idle Transfiguration Fight
Assimilate Mankind With Tengen
The Evolution of Mankind Throughout All Japan
The Culling Game's Objective
Colony
Idle Transfiguration
Modern Sorcerers
Incarnated Sorcerers
Those Whose Cursed
Techniques Awakened
Fight
The Culling Game: Rules
Stock Up Cursed Energy
Rule Forcing Them to Fight
Use Stocked-Up
Cursed Energy
to Move the Barriers
Designed to Ferry
the People of Japan
to the Other Side
10 Colonies Throughout Japan
Forced to Cross to the Other Side (= Cursed)
Warm-Up
Assimilate Mankind With Tengen
Itadori's Friends' Mission
1. Free Satoru Gojo
Tengen Possesses
Open Prison Realm Back
Obtain Prison Realm
Kenjaku Possess
Can't Do Without
the Front Gate
To Force It Open...
Inverted Spear
of Heaven
Black Rope
Angel
Culling Game Player
Satoru Gojo Destroyed
Miguel and Okkotsu Failed to Find
Technique That Extinguishes
All Cursed Techniques
In the Colony on the East Side of Tokyo
2. Rescue Tsumiki and
Reluctant Players
Consume 100 Points (Per Rules 6 and 7) to Add a Rule
7. ~Add a Rule Allowing Escape from the Culling Game
Persuade Players With 100 Points
and No Intention of Adding a Rule
Each Person's Actions
Maki
Go Retrieve Juzo Kumiya's Cursed Tools
Fushiguro Has Become
the Head of the Zen'in Clan
Go to the Zen'in Clan's Forbidden Vault
Meet Up With Panda
Okkotsu
Go On
Ahead Alone
Gather Information
Itadori    Fushiguro
Recruit Help
Recruit Kinji Hakari
Tsukumo      Choso
Guard Tengen
Participate in the Culling Game
Remain in the Tombs of the Star
Choso!
Thank you. You've been a big help.
Don't die out there.
Are you crying?
Shush.
Th-Thanks for tonight!
Takaba!
How long are ya gonna
keep doin' that crap?!
Cut it out!
You're making me depressed, too!
Yeah.
How old are ya now?
Thirty-five!
Then give it up already.
Our industry's full o' late-bloomers who
suddenly make it big for no good reason,
but none of 'em suddenly got funnier.
They were just funny people
waiting to be discovered.
And that ain't the case for you!
Look what happened to Tokyo.
No one's gonna think ill of you.
Go do something you're actually suited for.
I never disliked your comedy, Takaba.
Ken-san?
Both you and him have the wrong idea.
There's still people who ain't
funny that make it big.
You mean those with one stock gag?
Nah.
There are two types of comedians
that manage to stay big.
Comedians who are always funny,
and comedians who can always delude
themselves into believing they're funny.
Which one are you?
I'd say it's 50-50,
but it's actually 70-30...
50-50...
I'd say it's 50-50,
Culling Game Player
Fumihiko Takaba
but it's actually 70-30!
Mai, I'll get started.
Why did you come here?
Shall I bully you like I used to?
Then, please, you do it, Maki-san.
You are me, and I am you.
Make me happy I gave birth to you.
Absolutely ridiculous.
Destroy it all.
Next Episode
Perfect Preparation